# Michael Faulkner

3226 Benson Park Boulevard • Orlando, Florida 32829 • Phone: 321-303-1452 • E-Mail: elcid00@aol.com

## Summary

A motivated and results-oriented individual with experience in law enforcement, leadership, training, and operations. Ability to analyze complex situations and solve problems efficiently. A loyal and reliable individual, possessing knowledge, strength, and judgment able to work well in a team environment, or as a self-motivated independent contributor. Works well under pressure, and able to be successful in stressful and difficult circumstances. A people person, always willing to help others in any situation to achieve the desired results. Possesses strong oral and written communication skills, and efficient in the use of Microsoft Office suite.

## **Experience**

### Waterstone Mortgage Corporation

August 2016 – October 2018

Administrative Assistant, Loan Processor 1, Loan Processor 2

- Responsible for the processing of Conventional, FHA, VA, and Brokerage loans while maintaining compliance with existing government and investor guidelines
- Maintained excellent customer service with customers, co-workers, and other third parties through all phases of the loan process
- Perform initial pre-underwriting review of each loan file for accuracy and completeness, and verifying it is in accordance with program and investor guidelines
- · Responsible for managing pipeline and ensuring turn-times met at each stage and compliance requirements adhered to

#### ADT Security

December 2015 – July 2016

Residential Sales Representative

- Utilized strong communication and selling skills to present innovative security solutions to customers, overcome obstacles and close deals.
- Provide security consultations to customers including design, scope of work, and solution integration to meet customer needs.
- Cultivated new leads through referrals, company provided leads, networking groups, and cold-calling.
- Effectively managed territory to maximize daily production and customer relationships

#### City of Orlando, The Orlando Police Department

January 2003 – September 2015

Police Sergeant, January 2013 - September 2015

Police Corporal, January 2011 – January 2013

Police Officer, May 2003 - January 2011

- Supervise patrol officers in the function of their daily duties, providing guidance and feedback, and ensuring compliance with existing laws and department policies and procedures.
- Identify applicable crime trends and develop strategies to overcome.
- Provide training to patrol officers on existing policies and procedures, new policies and procedures, and topics to increase their overall job performance.
- Adept at communicating, verbally or written, with members of community and business owners.
- Preparation of multiple weekly reports for management, providing feedback on performance and objectives to meet the mission of the Department.
- Review and approval of all reports and documentation submitted by patrol officers, ensuring accuracy and completeness, compliance with department policies and procedures, and analysis for any potential trends requiring attention
- Coordinate efforts with other areas of department to utilize resources to achieve mission.

- Development of Operation Plans required for special events and details, and coordination of necessary resources
  within the Department and through external vendors. Completion of After Action Reports for the same, to provide
  results and recommendations for improvement to management.
- Served as a member of the Honor Guard for 7 years, representing the Orlando Police Department at various functions locally and nationally. Responsible for establishing and coordinating training for team on a quarterly basis.
- Served as a member of the Emergency Response Team for 11 years, participating in providing law enforcement duties
  during numerous protests and rallies with the expectation of potential violence. Provide training to team on various
  topics.

## Valencia Community College

March 2012 – September 2015

Criminal Justice Institute, Adjunct Instructor

- Provide instruction during 40-hour Basic Police Mountain Bike course through practical and classroom instruction
- Assist with completion of required documentation to maintain compliance with requirements of college, state, and Law Enforcement Bicycle Association
- Prior to obtaining instructor certification, assisted with course preparation, practical instruction and compliance of safety protocols from 2007 thru 2012

### SunTrust Bank

September 2001 – January 2003

Migration Analyst (Act-1 Personnel Services Contract)

- Part of Online Treasury Management team, responsible for assisting business clients with transition to new online software.
- Provide training to clients via telephone for integration to new software.
- Provide technical support and completing proper referrals for more complex issues.
- Track progression and efficiency of entire team, providing feedback to management.

### Maxcess Telecommunications Company

August 2000 – May 2001

Financial Analyst

- Use of SQL coding in the analysis of data usage received from telecommunication providers.
- Establish procedures to reduce the potential loss of revenue as a result of corrupted and reporting errors within usage data
- Collaborate with Customer Service Representatives in handling customer issues related to billed usage data.

## Additional Experience

- Institute of Internal Auditors Administrative Assistant
- Government Employees Mortgage Company Administrative Assistant
- Baker Brothers, Inc. Warehouse Worker

## **Education**

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, Minor in Management Information Systems
The Citadel, Military College of South Carolina
August 1996 – May 2000